# **URMI SEN**

### **OBJECTIVES**

I have been working with Machine Learning and Data Science for about 2.5 years. Currently working on data analytical and different data driven predictive projects. My main motto is to collaborate in the field of Data Science and to make some contributions to humankind with the knowledge of back-end development along with ML project implementations.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### **Junior Data Analyst**

<sup>O</sup> Shikho Technologies Bangladesh LTD

June 2022 - Present

- Extracting, cleaning, Querying, and summarizing data from PostgreSQL databases to be able to meet business requirements.
- Analyzing external and internal customer data using database queries (SQL,postgresSQL) and producing meaningful reports, visualizations, and predictive models for various departments throughout the company.
- Automating all processes around Data extraction and Data Transformation for the dashboard by combining python with PostgresSQL and MySql.

## **Undergraduate Research Student**

' Machine Learning Research Group

Aug 2019 - Dec 2021

- Published a research paper under the supervision of Dr. Md. Al Mehedi Hasan Sir, Professor, Department of Computer Science Engineering, Rajshahi University of Engineering Technology. (Link)

### SKILLS & INTERESTS

**Research Domains**: Data Science, Machine Learning, Deep Learning,

Computer Vision, Bioinformatics

**Programming Languages**: Python, C/C++,SQL, Postgresql, HTML, CSS

Tools: Git, Excel, Google Sheets, Tableau, metabase, CleverTap

Interpersonal Skills: Leadership, Communication Skill, Teamwork, Management

Languages: English: Full professional proficiency

Bengali: Full professional proficiency

## STANDARDIZED TEST SCORES

International English Language Testing System (IELTS) - 27th August, 2022

Overall Band Score	Listening	Reading	Writing	Speaking
6.5	7.0	6.0	6.0	6.5

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

- O Exploratory Data Analysis in Python. (Link)
- O Data Visualization with Python , IBM. (Link)
- Introduction to Machine Learning, Kaggle. (Link)

- Introduction to Natural Language Processing in Python, Datacamp.(Link)
- O Neural Networks and Deep Learning, DEEPLEARNING.AI, Coursera. (Link)
- O Hyperparameter tuning, Regularization and Optimization, DEEPLEARNING.AI, Coursera. (Link)

## **EDUCATION**

**B.Sc.** in Computer Science & Engineering

Rajshahi, Bangladesh

Rajshahi University of Engineering & Technology (RUET),

2016 - 2022

- CGPA: 3.38 out of 4.00

Higher Secondary Certificate (H.S.C.)

Shahid Syed Nazrul Islam College,

Mymensingh, Bangladesh

2013 - 2014

- CGPA: 5.00 out of 5.00

Secondary School Certificate (S.S.C.)

Mymensingh, Bangladesh

2011 - 2012

Premier Ideal High School,
- CGPA: 5.00 out of 5.00

## **PUBLICATIONS**

DeepGlut: A Deep Learning Framework for Prediction of Glutarylation Sites in Proteins

**Authers**: Urmi Sen , Md. Al Mehedi Hasan.

Status: Available Online.

**Conference**: IEEE Region 10 Symposium

Publisher: IEEE

Field: Bioinformatics

**DOI**: 10.1109/TENSYMP50017.2020.9230866

## **Projects**

### **Programming:**

- OOP & Data Structure. (Link)
- Basics of python programming. (Link)
- O Data manipulation and data visualization with python. (Link)

#### **Lab Automation System:**

- It's a "Lab Automation" system with features like which lab have how many computer with configuration
  of those computers and one can know which applications are installed on that computer by one click.
- o php laravel framework was used. (Link)

#### **Student- Faculty Management System:**

- It's a system where a faculty member can manage students profile by adding, editing and deleting data, can publish class test marks and result etc and student can create and handle their accounts and get the notifications.
- Python Framework Django was used. (Link)

#### **Machine Learning Implementations:**

- All my implemented Machine Learning projects. All implemented Machine Learning projects and learnings from different ML courses and blogs are reflected here. (Link)
- All my implementions from The Sparks Foundation task-list till now with diiferent Machine Learning Techniques. (Link)

#### Sequence data classification using CNN:

O Built a CNN model to predict PTM sites in protein sequences using Keras .Further cross validation also held to evaluate the performance of the model. (Link)

#### PERSONAL DETAILS

**Date of Birth**: February 12, 1998

Gender: Female
Nationality: Bangladeshi
Religion: Hinduism
National Id No.: 915 520 6072
Passport No: B00043627

Passport Issue Date: April 21, 2022

**Blood Group**: B(+ve)

## REFERENCES

#### Dr. Md. Al Mehedi Hasan

Dr. Md. Ali Hossain

Professor

Professor Department of Computer Science and Engineering Rajshahi University of Engineering and Technology Rajshahi-6204

Department of Computer Science and Engineering Rajshahi University of Engineering and Technology Rajshahi-6204

I hereby certify that all the information provided above is true in best of my knowledge and sense and well supported by legal documents.

Thanks.

Urmi Sen